Subtitle Provide by dramacool.asia Translator [Admin.@YNG]
تم توفير الترجمة بواسطة مترجم dramacool.asia [Admin.@YNG]
♪Passing by where leaves fall and flowers fade♪
♪المرور حيث تتساقط الأوراق وتذبل الزهور♪
♪Chancing upon shooting stars and northern lights♪
♪الصدفة على النجوم المتساقطة والأضواء الشمالية♪
♪At this moment, I borrow the wind♪
♪في هذه اللحظة، أستعير الريح♪
♪To set sail for distant seas♪
♪للإبحار إلى البحار البعيدة♪
♪Rumors swirl close to my ears♪
♪تدور الشائعات بالقرب من أذني♪
♪Some laugh and say my dreams are wild♪
♪يضحك البعض ويقولون أن أحلامي جامحة♪
♪Yet I will not change my original aspiration♪
♪ولكنني لن أغير طموحاتي الأصلية♪
♪Even if it means running into a wall♪
♪حتى لو كان ذلك يعني الاصطدام بالحائط♪
♪I know the road to growing up brings pain♪
♪أعلم أن الطريق إلى النمو يجلب الألم♪
♪Still, I hold fast to the dream I cherish♪
♪ما زلت متمسكًا بالحلم الذي أعتز به♪
♪Never have I thought to yield♪
♪لم أفكر أبدًا في الاستسلام♪
♪Youth is meant to stand against the world♪
♪الشباب هو من المفترض أن يقف في وجه العالم♪
♪I've always longed♪
♪لقد تمنيتها دائما♪
♪To stand upon the highest peak♪
♪الوقوف على أعلى قمة♪
♪I've always wished♪
♪لقد تمنيت دائما♪
♪To cross a river wide and deep♪
♪لأعبر نهرًا واسعًا وعميقًا♪
♪In darkness, look up to see the sky turn clear♪
♪في الظلام، انظر إلى الأعلى لترى السماء تصبح صافية♪
♪Unyielding♪
♪لا يلين♪
♪The butterfly reborn from its cocoon must fly♪
♪الفراشة التي تولد من شرنقتها يجب أن تطير♪
♪Like bamboo breaking forth, I chase dreams through hardship♪
♪مثل الخيزران الذي ينبت، أطارد الأحلام من خلال المشقة♪
♪Return to me, my dream♪
♪ارجع إليّ يا حلمي♪
♪Unyielding♪
♪لا يلين♪
♪My pure heart stays the same♪
♪قلبي النقي يبقى كما هو♪
♪You must face the wind♪
♪يجب عليك مواجهة الريح♪
♪And go where your heart leads♪
♪واذهب إلى حيث يقودك قلبك♪
♪Embrace the moonlight that belongs to you♪
♪احتضن ضوء القمر الذي ينتمي إليك♪
♪In the dark♪
♪في الظلام♪
=Voyage to Haihun, Season 2=
=رحلة إلى هايهون، الموسم الثاني=
=Episode 24=
=الحلقة 24=
Yes, someone is robbing a tomb.
نعم، هناك شخص يسرق قبرًا.
It's the place I just mentioned.
هذا هو المكان الذي ذكرته للتو.
Officer, please come quickly.
سيدي الضابط، من فضلك تعال بسرعة.
Who are you talking to?
من الذي تتحدث معه؟
The police.
الشرطة.
So this is the police?
إذن هذه هي الشرطة؟
No, it's a mobile phone.
لا، إنه هاتف محمول.
It's the latest model.
إنه أحدث نموذج.
My mom bought it for me.
لقد اشترته لي أمي.
If she hadn't sent it to me,
لو لم ترسلها لي،
I'd still have no idea where she is.
لا زلت لا أملك أي فكرة عن مكانها.
Has it been long since you saw her?
هل مر وقت طويل منذ أن رأيتها؟
Ever since she divorced my father,
منذ أن طلقت والدي،
I haven't seen her again.
لم أراها مرة أخرى.
Devour soul?
التهام الروح؟
Such a sinister art truly exists.
إن مثل هذا الفن الشرير موجود بالفعل.
When I was very young,
عندما كنت صغيرا جدا،
both my parents passed away.
لقد توفي كلا والدي.
So for me,
بالنسبة لي،
seeing them is impossible.
رؤيتهم مستحيلة.
Didn't expect you to be so pitiful.
لم أتوقع أن تكون مثيرًا للشفقة إلى هذه الدرجة.
But I have a lot of buddies.
ولكن لدي الكثير من الأصدقاء.
One of them is truly unusual.
واحد منهم غير عادي حقا.
How unusual?
كم هو غير عادي؟
Is he amazing?
هل هو مذهل؟
He always comes up with
انه يأتي دائما مع
all sorts of strange, wild ideas.
كل أنواع الأفكار الغريبة والبرية.
He's helped me solve many problems.
لقد ساعدني في حل العديد من المشاكل.
And he's skilled at parkour.
وهو ماهر في رياضة الباركور.
What's parkour?
ما هو الباركور؟
Sounds cool just from the name.
يبدو رائعًا فقط من الاسم.
Jumping up and down all over the place,
القفز لأعلى ولأسفل في كل مكان،
like running across rooftops.
مثل الجري عبر أسطح المنازل.
Oh, that I know well.
أوه، هذا ما أعرفه جيدًا.
I do it every day in the school.
أفعل ذلك كل يوم في المدرسة.
Isn't it just climbing walls?
أليس الأمر مجرد تسلق الجدران؟
That's one way to put it.
هذه إحدى الطرق لقول ذلك.
Then train hard.
ثم تدرب بجد.
You'll need it someday.
سوف تحتاجها يوما ما.
Mm.
مم.
Interesting.
مثير للاهتمام.
My house
بيتي
is several times taller than the highest building here.
أطول بعدة مرات من أعلى مبنى هنا.
At night, the whole city glows with lights.
في الليل، تتوهج المدينة بأكملها بالأضواء.
So bright you can't see the stars.
إنها مشرقة جدًا لدرجة أنك لا تستطيع رؤية النجوم.
The carriages need no horses.
العربات لا تحتاج إلى خيول.
They move on their own.
إنهم يتحركون من تلقاء أنفسهم.
My wish
أمنيتي
has finally come true.
لقد أصبح حقيقة أخيرا.
This is for you.
هذا لك.
What is it?
ما هذا؟
Bronze Qilin.
تشيلين البرونزية.
Half for you, half for me.
نصف لك ونصف لي
Consider it a token of our brotherhood.
اعتبرها رمزًا لأخوتنا.
Who said I'm your buddy?
من قال أني صديقك؟
We've been talking for a while.
لقد تحدثنا لبعض الوقت.
There's at least a bit of bond.
هناك على الأقل القليل من الرابطة.
I hold my buddies to high standards.
أحمل أصدقائي معايير عالية.
It's not a bit of.
إنه ليس شيئا من ذلك.
It's the tiniest bit.
إنه الجزء الأصغر.
I'm only giving you this as a buddy.
أنا أعطيك هذا كصديق فقط.
Think of it as a charm for protection.
اعتبرها بمثابة تعويذة للحماية.
There's also a spell to keep you safe.
هناك أيضًا تعويذة لإبقائك آمنًا.
Really?
حقًا؟
Mm.
مم.
Bronze Qilin,
الكيلين البرونزي،
guard the universe.
حماية الكون.
The firmament shines,
السماء تشرق،
granting my wish.
تحقيق رغبتي.
Changes are cyclical,
التغييرات دورية،
eternal as sun and moon.
أبدي كالشمس والقمر.
Unveil the mysteries,
اكشف الأسرار
all at my command.
كل ذلك تحت أمري.
Got it memorized?
هل حفظته؟
Mm.
مم.
Really?
حقًا؟
Who are you looking down on?
من الذي تنظر إليه من الأسفل؟
I've got a great memory.
لقد حصلت على ذاكرة عظيمة.
It's all because of you.
كل هذا بفضلك .
Chatting with you
الدردشة معك
made me miss my stop.
جعلني أفتقد توقفي.
Sir,
سيد،
I need to get off.
أحتاج إلى النزول.
Remember our promise.
تذكر وعدنا.
What promise?
ما الوعد؟
The authority received a report,
وتلقت الهيئة بلاغاً،
(Nanchang, Jiangxi) saying someone engaged
(نانتشانغ، جيانغشي) قائلا شخص مخطوب
(Police) in grave robbing.
(الشرطة) في نبش القبور.
The police acted swiftly,
لقد تحركت الشرطة بسرعة،
working with the archaeology team.
العمل مع فريق الآثار.
They headed to the site for investigation.
توجهوا إلى الموقع للتحقيق.
After the initial survey,
بعد المسح الأولي،
it was confirmed to be a grand Han Dynasty tomb.
وقد تم التأكد من أنها مقبرة عظيمة تعود إلى عهد أسرة هان.
Some experts suggested
واقترح بعض الخبراء
the owner might be Liu He, the first Haihun Marquis.
ربما يكون المالك هو ليو هي، ماركيز هايهون الأول.
You're awake.
أنت مستيقظ.
Don't move.
.لا تتحرك
Here, look at me.
انظر إليّ.
How many fingers?
كم عدد الاصابع؟
Look here.
أنظر هنا.
Why am I here?
لماذا انا هنا؟
You were in a car accident.
لقد تعرضت لحادث سيارة.
You've been unconscious for 27 days.
لقد كنت فاقدًا للوعي لمدة 27 يومًا.
Twenty-seven days?
سبعة وعشرون يوما؟
Twenty-seven...
سبعة وعشرون...
What are you looking for?
ما الذي تبحث عنه؟
Is this what you're after?
هل هذا ما تبحث عنه؟
They're yours.
إنهم لك.
Where are you going?
إلى أين أنت ذاهب؟
(Nurse Station) You just woke up.
(محطة التمريض) لقد استيقظت للتو.
(Nanchang Relic Museum For Haihun Principality)
(متحف نانتشانغ للآثار لإمارة هايهون)
(Golden Haihun)
(الولادة الذهبية)
(The Exhibition of the History and Culture of Haihun Principality in the Han Dynasty)
(معرض تاريخ وثقافة إمارة هايهون في عهد أسرة هان)
♪Night flows♪
♪تدفقات الليل♪
♪Over the window frames and treetops♪
♪فوق إطارات النوافذ وقمم الأشجار♪
Did I say you could come in?
هل قلت لك أنه بإمكانك الدخول؟
♪Sinking into the night♪
♪الغرق في الليل♪
It's been eleven years.
لقد مرت إحدى عشر سنة.
Eleven years!
إحدى عشر سنة!
They're all gone now.
لقد رحلوا جميعا الآن.
I thought you were gone too.
اعتقدت أنك ذهبت أيضًا.
♪Writing continues♪
♪ الكتابة مستمرة ♪
♪Paper gently sways♪
♪الورق يتأرجح بلطف♪
Heng,
هنغ،
remember this well.
تذكر هذا جيدا.
The ink-inscribed gold ingots in my tomb
سبائك الذهب المنقوشة بالحبر في قبري
must always be in abundance.
يجب أن يكون دائما بوفرة.
At the very least,
على أقل تقدير،
no fewer than this amount.
لا يقل عن هذا المبلغ.
I know, one hundred.
أنا أعلم، مائة.
A thousand?
ألف؟
- One hundred thousand. - What?
- مائة ألف. - ماذا؟
Better more than less.
من الأفضل أكثر من أقل.
♪Between us♪
♪بيننا♪
♪There are lines of unspoken words♪
♪هناك أسطر من الكلمات غير المنطوقة♪
This Horse-hoof Gold looks different from what I recall.
يبدو هذا الحصان ذو الحوافر الذهبية مختلفًا عما أتذكره.
They're far too uneven.
إنهم غير متساويين للغاية.
♪A moment caught at my fingertips♪
♪لحظة تم التقاطها في متناول يدي♪
What should they look like?
كيف ينبغي أن يبدوا؟
Anything but this.
أي شيء إلا هذا.
♪Between my lips and teeth♪
♪بين شفتي وأسناني♪
♪Burning with words left unsaid♪
♪محترق بالكلمات التي لم تُقال♪
The third item
البند الثالث
is this Chi Niu Jade Seall.
هذا هو عرض تشي نيو اليشم.
This piece
هذه القطعة
was something I always wore when in Changyi.
كان هذا شيئًا كنت أرتديه دائمًا عندما كنت في تشانغي.
It marked my rank as the Duke of Changyi.
لقد حددت رتبتي كدوق تشانغي.
Now that I think back...
الآن بعد أن أفكر مرة أخرى...
♪Cuddling together♪
♪الاحتضان معًا♪
♪Our journey becomes a painting♪
♪رحلتنا تصبح لوحة فنية♪
those days
تلك الأيام
were the happiest time of my life.
لقد كانت أسعد أوقات حياتي.
♪The warmth in my hands fades away♪
♪الدفء في يدي يتلاشى♪
♪The arc-shaped jade hangs low♪
♪اليشم على شكل قوس يتدلى منخفضًا♪
♪Fragrance lingering in the sleeves♪
♪العطر يعلق في الأكمام♪
♪The topic ferments♪
♪الموضوع يتخمر♪
♪Lingering on♪
♪البقاء على قيد الحياة♪
♪Words drift and waver in the wind♪
♪الكلمات تتجول وتتمايل في الريح♪
The first
الأول
Changyi Riders Racing with the Wind
فرسان تشانغي يتسابقون مع الريح
begins!
يبدأ!
Come on. You can do it.
هيا، يمكنك فعل ذلك.
♪My gaze met the dark waves♪
♪نظرتي التقت بالأمواج المظلمة♪
♪I raised a cup to hide my restless heart♪
♪رفعت كأسًا لأخفي قلبي المضطرب♪
♪My little courage♪
♪شجاعتي الصغيرة♪
♪Turned into falling snow♪
♪تحولت إلى ثلوج متساقطة♪
♪A thousand unspoken words♪
♪ألف كلمة غير منطوقة♪
Did you bring the Blank Seal I gave you?
هل أحضرت الختم الفارغ الذي أعطيتك إياه؟
How could I not bring the finest jade?
كيف لا أستطيع أن أحضر أجود أنواع اليشم؟
Let me tell you something.
دعني أخبرك بشيء.
On this journey, focus on just one thing.
في هذه الرحلة، ركز على شيء واحد فقط.
What?
ماذا؟
Just think about
فقط فكر في
what rank would you want
ما هي الرتبة التي تريدها
to be engraved in that seal.
ليتم نقشها في هذا الختم.
After all, we're heading to Chang'an to prove ourselves.
بعد كل شيء، نحن متجهون إلى تشانغآن لإثبات أنفسنا.
I can't give you the official seal.
لا أستطيع أن أعطيك الختم الرسمي.
But you look like the turtle up there,
لكنك تبدو مثل السلحفاة هناك،
both hiding the heads.
كلاهما يخفي الرؤوس.
♪Burning with words left unsaid♪
♪محترق بالكلمات التي لم تُقال♪
You're the one hiding like a turtle.
أنت الشخص الذي يختبئ مثل السلحفاة.
Marquis, when will you
ماركيز متى سوف
grant me an official post in Haihun?
هل تمنحني منصبًا رسميًا في هايهون؟
♪Heartstrings tangled in chaos♪
♪أوتار القلب متشابكة في الفوضى♪
Not back to Chang'an?
لم تعد إلى تشانغآن؟
♪The fleeting mist♪
♪الضباب العابر♪
Not going back.
لا عودة.
If my nephew, the Emperor,
إذا كان ابن أخي الإمبراطور،
made you Great General,
لقد جعلتك جنرالًا عظيمًا،
would you go back?
هل ستعود؟
I wouldn't go.
لن اذهب .
I'll stay here in Haihun.
سأبقى هنا في هايهون.
Wait for my return.
انتظر عودتي
Carve this official title for me.
نحت هذا اللقب الرسمي بالنسبة لي.
That's the task I'm giving you.
هذه هي المهمة التي أعطيك إياها.
(I know every relic here by heart.)
(أنا أعرف كل الآثار هنا عن ظهر قلب.)
(No one else knows)
(لا أحد يعرف غيري)
(why this jade seal bears no words.)
(لماذا لا يحمل ختم اليشم هذا أي كلمات.)
(Now I understand.)
(الآن فهمت.)
(Though I didn't go back,)
(على الرغم من أنني لم أعود)
(you kept waiting for me.)
(كنت تنتظرني.)
♪One more glance♪
♪نظرة أخرى♪
♪Longing to touch your hair♪
♪أشتاق إلى لمس شعرك♪
♪Looking back♪
♪النظر إلى الوراء♪
♪No more worlds apart♪
♪لا مزيد من العوالم المنفصلة♪
Sir, excuse me,
سيدي، عذرا،
would you like a guide?
هل تريد دليلا؟
♪Etched like grains of sand in time♪
♪محفورة مثل حبات الرمل في الزمن♪
♪Burning hot♪
♪حارق للغاية♪
De Jiu.
دي جيو.
I think you've mistaken me.
أعتقد أنك أخطأتني.
My name is San.
اسمي سان.
♪Twin shadows in the setting sun♪
♪ظلال توأم في غروب الشمس♪
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
I did mistake you.
لقد أخطأت في حقك.
♪Our hearts as one♪
♪قلوبنا واحدة♪
♪Mark time♪
♪حدد الوقت♪
♪Time may shift♪
♪قد يتغير الزمن♪
♪Yet we fear no more♪
♪ولكننا لم نعد نخاف بعد الآن♪
♪Night winds sweep away♪
♪رياح الليل تكتسح♪
♪The unsent letters♪
♪الرسائل غير المرسلة♪
♪That confession♪
♪هذا الاعتراف♪
♪Still rings around♪
♪لا يزال يرن في كل مكان♪
Don't forget our gift 2,000 years from now.
لا تنسى هديتنا بعد 2000 سنة من الآن.
I've already picked the place.
لقد اخترت المكان بالفعل.
Land of Haihun.
أرض هايهون.
Reverse winding path.
مسار متعرج عكسي.
In Haihun,
في هايهون،
go against the wind
الذهاب ضد الريح
for 50 li.
لـ 50 لي.
At the south of the waters.
في جنوب المياه.
Land of Yongxiu.
أرض يونغ شيو.
Sunset glows.
غروب الشمس يضيء.
Three steps east.
ثلاث خطوات شرقا.
Nine steps north.
تسع خطوات نحو الشمال.
Chisel the turtle head place,
إزميل مكان رأس السلحفاة،
and the treasure will emerge.
وسوف يظهر الكنز.
Luo,
لوه،
give me a hand.
أعطني يد المساعدة.
(Wucheng Town, Yongxiu County)
(مدينة ووتشنغ، مقاطعة يونغشيو)
(Turtle Mountain)
(جبل السلحفاة)
Hey, Luo.
مهلا، لو.
Hey, Wang Heng.
مرحبًا وانغ هينج.
Found it.
وجدته.
At Turtle Mountain.
في جبل السلحفاة.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
In Haihun,
في هايهون،
go against the wind
الذهاب ضد الريح
for 50 li.
لـ 50 لي.
(Turtle Mountain) At the south of the waters.
(جبل السلحفاة) جنوب المياه.
Chisel the turtle head place,
إزميل مكان رأس السلحفاة،
and the treasure will emerge.
وسوف يظهر الكنز.
Never thought that 2,000 years later,
لم أكن أتصور أبدًا أنه بعد مرور 2000 عام،
you'd still call me a coward like turtle.
لا تزال تناديني بالجبان مثل السلحفاة.
You've got some nerve.
لقد حصلت على بعض الشجاعة.
Luo, Luo!
لوه لوه!
Luo.
لوه.
Wang Heng!
وانغ هنغ!
Tell me, is this the one?
أخبرني هل هذا هو؟
Alright, guys, wrap it up.
حسنًا يا شباب، أنهوا الأمر.
Bronze Qilin,
الكيلين البرونزي،
guard the universe.
حماية الكون.
The firmament shines,
السماء تشرق،
granting my wish.
تحقيق رغبتي.
Changes are cyclical,
التغييرات دورية،
eternal as sun and moon.
أبدي كالشمس والقمر.
Unveil the mysteries,
اكشف الأسرار
all at my command.
كل ذلك تحت أمري.
=Voyage to Haihun= (The End)
=رحلة إلى هايهون= (النهاية)
♪Watch the storm; hear the night rain fall♪
♪شاهد العاصفة؛ استمع إلى صوت هطول المطر في الليل♪
♪Till the light of dawn♪
♪حتى ضوء الفجر♪
♪A truth that cannot be spoken♪
♪حقيقة لا يمكن التحدث بها♪
♪Right and wrong matter♪
♪الصواب والخطأ مهمان♪
♪Yet I can't make the right choice♪
♪ولكن لا أستطيع اتخاذ الاختيار الصحيح♪
♪The lost player in the game♪
♪اللاعب الخاسر في اللعبة♪
♪Made a move by a twist of fate♪
♪لقد اتخذت خطوة بسبب تقلب القدر♪
♪The way back is lost, leaving nowhere to return♪
♪لقد ضاع طريق العودة، ولم يبق مكان للعودة♪
♪Borrow the endless cycles♪
♪استعارة الدورات التي لا نهاية لها♪
♪To fight for the most perfect outcome♪
♪القتال من أجل الحصول على النتيجة الأكثر مثالية♪
♪How to trace the threads and follow cause and effect♪
♪كيفية تتبع الخيوط واتباع السبب والنتيجة♪
♪Seeking a strategy without flaw♪
♪البحث عن استراتيجية خالية من العيوب♪
♪How to break free from this fated yet unforeseen lock♪
♪كيفية التحرر من هذا القفل المقدر وغير المتوقع♪
♪To live so as to shake the world♪
♪العيش من أجل هز العالم♪
♪With this journey, I gain a fiercer edge♪
♪مع هذه الرحلة، اكتسبت حافة أكثر شراسة♪
♪I've planned before I act countless times♪
♪لقد خططت قبل أن أتصرف مرات لا تحصى♪
♪Fatal danger turned into a jest♪
♪خطر قاتل تحول إلى مزحة♪
♪Through this road, I watch the endless rise and fall♪
♪من خلال هذا الطريق، أشاهد الصعود والهبوط الذي لا نهاية له♪
♪In the chapters lie ages of decay and bloom♪
♪في الفصول تكمن عصور من الاضمحلال والازدهار♪
♪Let us meet again♪
♪دعونا نلتقي مرة أخرى♪
♪One hurried path, and one at ease♪
♪مسار واحد سريع، ومسار آخر مريح♪